# Alexander **Papiez**

Research Chemist

#### Contact

31 Ashfield Road Gosforth Newcastle Upon Tyne NE3 4XL

alex.papiez@gmail.com

Tel:07948373631

# **Key Skills**

- 7 Years laboratory experience
- · Tutoring experience
- Competent user of LATEXtypesetting software
- Knowledge of the Python programming language
- Experienced user of Microsoft Office packages
- Ability to maintain confidentiality
- Excellent spelling and grammar
- Ability to work to a deadline/ under pressure

Full U.K. Driving licence

References available on request

#### **Personal Statement**

I began studying for my PhD in the physical chemistry of polymers in the summer of 2013. My post-graduate research experience has allowed me to grow as an independent researcher while co-operating closely with others to achieve research objectives.

During my academic career, I have been required to present my research both internally (for examination and peer review) and externally (at conferences and to my industrial sponsor); I have become highly adept and presenting complex information in a clear and concise fashion in a manner appropriate for the audience at the time.

# **Education**

09/2013-Present PhD in Physical Polymer Chemistry

Northumbria University

Supervisors: Dr. Justin Perry and Dr. Leslie Dix

Funded by: AkzoNobel

Thesis title: Investigating the Rate of Release of Ions Across Polymer

Phases

Summary: In order to develop competitive products in a sustainable

manner, antifouling paint manufacturers must consider the kinetics of biocide release. By studying the diffusion rate of biocides in relation to material properties, insights useful for the rational design of antifouling technologies may be found.

Publications: Papiez, A.P. Perry, J.J.B Ferguson, J. Wright, A.C.

Diffusion of Biocides in Polymeric Matricies: A Tool for Rational Coating Design, Poster presented at the Interational Congress on Marine Corrosion and Fouling, Toulon France, 2016;

**Papiez**, A.P. Perry, J.J.B. Downs, R.A. *Design and Implementation of a 3D Printed Microwave Flow Cell*, Poster presented at the R.S.C.

Organic division meeting, Bradford, U.K. 2015

09/2009 - 06/2013 MChem Applied Chemistry

Northumbria University

Classification: 1st with honours

Awards: Best Post-graduate final-year project, 2013

4th Year Synthesis and Characterization of Amino Functionalized

Project: Methacrylate Polymers

# **Employment**

10/2013 - 04/2014 **Data-Entry/Q.A. Assistant** 

Tata Global Beverages, Eaglescliffe

Selecting samples from production lines, preparing tissue samples, conducting various quality tests, recording data in Microsoft Excel.

12/2012 - 10/2013 Production operative / Packer

Quorn Foods, Stokesley

Working as part of a team on the Production Line. Duties include packing, palletising, 'spotting', cleaning, some work in 'high-care' production areas.

11/2012 - 12/2012 Temporary Administrative Assistant

Univar Europe, Middlesbrough

General administrative/clerical duties including typing, filing,

scanning/photocopying/faxing, emailing, answering the telephone, dataentry (Microsoft Office, Excel, Outlook, Word). The company were in the process of migrating to new office management software and I was involved in the scanning, uploading and data-entry of mass documents into SAP.

#### 1996-2004 Personal Assistant to my ex-husband

Freelance IT consultancy

Typing, filing, answering the telephone, making travel arrangements, preparing invoices etc.

#### 07/1980 - 04/1991 **Deparmental Assistant**

Teesside University; Computer Centre

Provision of clerical and secretarial support to senior staff, production/typing of minutes and correspondence (from dictation or audio), technical documents, PhD theses etc. Conference organisation, reception duties including setting-up student and staff accounts on the computer systems. Ordering stationery, recording holidays and sickness, organising travel and accommodation for Centre staff.

#### 11/1978 - 07-1980 **Shorthand/Typist**

Teesside University; Central Administration

As a member of the Typing Pool, providing a typing service to Administrative and other university staff. This job also involved being seconded to academic departments to provide secretarial support.

08/1978 - 11/1978 **Shorthand/Typist/Clerk** 

Cleveland Probation Service; Headquarters

Providing secretarial support to the Administrative Officer.

# **Voluntary Work**

2004 Shop Assistant

Help the Aged, Stokesley

01/1985 - 07/1986 **Sub-Warden** Teesside University (Polytechnic); Middleton-St-George Halls of Residence This residential post involved assisting students with any problems regarding their accommodation, arranging for repairs and maintenance with the senior warden, inspecting rooms and booking in/out students at the start and end of term, carrying out fire-drills.